<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Dommett</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Dommett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular orbital theory</title>
      <link>/post/molecular-orbital-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/molecular-orbital-theory/</guid>
      <description>Last week I held a tutorial for undergraduate chemistry students about molecular orbital theory. I really enjoyed going over the fundamental principles on quantum chemistry, and as such wanted to write a short post on the basics.
Molecular orbital theory is a somewhat crude approximation to allow us to calculate the energy of an electron in an orbital, forming the basis for calculating the energy of a molecule using, for example, the self-consistent field procedure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to grips with MySQL</title>
      <link>/post/getting-to-grips-with-mysql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-to-grips-with-mysql/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few months I have been using MySQL to locally archive, store, and access data for a few of my projects. Previously, I was using Excel for this purpose, but I have come to find it less than ideal, mainly due to its clunkiness and the fact that I got into bad habits (no vesion control, poor formatting, rudimentary analyses). As such, I decided to switch to a combination of MySQL and python with pandas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing my first scientific paper</title>
      <link>/post/publishing-my-first-scientific-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/publishing-my-first-scientific-paper/</guid>
      <description>At the end of 2016, Rachel Crespo-Otero and I received news that our submitted manuscript was to be published in the journal Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. It was a great piece of news to receive before the Christmas holidays and was met with both joy and relief. It was the culmination of 12 months of work - the manuscript had taken many guises before we were happy enough to submit. This was my first scientific publication and in this post I want to give some background into the project, how we approached the problem, and the process of publishing in a peer-reviewed academic journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 09:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>How Inter- and Intramolecular Processes Dictate Aggregation-Induced Emission in Crystals Undergoing Excited-State Proton Transfer
Excited State Intramolecular Proton Transfer in 2&amp;rsquo;-Hydroxychalcone Derivatives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I model how light and atoms interact, and how we can use this to our advantage in technology.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>